<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Logs on Abhinav VP</title><link>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/</link><description>Recent content in Logs on Abhinav VP</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>[Home](/) &amp;#183; Theme [Simpleness](https://github.com/RainerChiang/simpleness) Powered by [Hugo](https://gohugo.io/)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>#7 Ditching the below Idea</title><link>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/7/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/7/</guid><description>Discused it with a friend of mine who asked the obvious question :
but why ? Till now I had two repositories for my blog, one to host the github data and markdown files, and the other to serve the blog.
Which led to some mundane task to publish the posts.
Ill have to push the changes to one branch, then generate the webpage and serve it to another repo.</description></item><item><title>#6 Idea for automating this daily logger</title><link>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/6/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/6/</guid><description>Improved the UI for Profilinator
Changed the theme for hugo blog
Slept the whole evening 0-0
A daily blog using Github Gist Github APIs have an option to fetch gists of any user. The gists can be saved in markdown as well. It could be possible to use Gists to save daily logs, which can be fetched and converted to HTML and displayed in the browser using Javascript. Need to check further more.</description></item><item><title>#5 Created a simple landing page</title><link>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/5/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/5/</guid><description>Profilinator is web app that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for past few months. It generates a downloadable html porfolio website from given input fields.
Even though there are some other applications that does the same, this one has an extra feature of generating data from Github and Devto profiles of the user. The data generation is using API calls that does not require authentication.
An extra feature would be to use Linkedin profile to generate data, that could be a real gamechanger.</description></item><item><title>#4 Profilinator: Update</title><link>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/4/</guid><description>Profilinator is web app that I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on for past few months. It generates a downloadable html porfolio website from given input fields.
Even though there are some other applications that does the same, this one has an extra feature of generating data from Github and Devto profiles of the user. The data generation is using API calls that does not require authentication.
An extra feature would be to use Linkedin profile to generate data, that could be a real gamechanger.</description></item><item><title>#3 PostgreSQL notes II</title><link>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/3/</guid><description>Chapter 3. Advanced Feature Views a name to the query that you can refer to CREATE VIEW myview AS SELECT name, temp_lo, temp_hi, prcp, date, location FROM weather, cities WHERE city = name; SELECT * FROM myview;
Foreign Keys to make sure that no one can insert rows in the one table that do not have a matching entry in another table. This is called maintaining the referential integrity of your data.</description></item><item><title>#2 PostgreSQL notes I</title><link>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/2/</guid><description>Tutorial Chapter 1. Tutorial Create a database createdb dbname* Delete a database dropdb dbname* To start psql to interact with database psql dbname* To view tables in database \t Chapter 2. The SQL Language PostgreSQL is a relational database management system (RDBMS). That means it is a system for managing data stored in relations. Relation is essentially a mathematical term for table Creating a New Table CREATE TABLE weather ( city varchar(80), temp_lo int, &amp;ndash; low temperature temp_hi int, &amp;ndash; high temperature prcp real, &amp;ndash; precipitation date date );</description></item><item><title>#1 Decided to learn SQL in depth</title><link>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.abhinavvp.com/logs/1/</guid><description>I had learned SQL back in college, which gave me an idea about how databases work, transactions, relations etc. I have mostly focused on Front end technologies, since I had found them more interesting and creative than the Back end.
On joining Ceegees Software Solutions back in 2021, I have been working on a web application which uses NestJs with PostgreSQL and typeOrm for the backend. I was able to achieve most of the features with my basic knowledge of sql and typeOrm, but it feels like going in depth like I have with the front end will help me understand and create better, error devoid code.</description></item></channel></rss>